# MARK CHRISTOPHER HARRIS, PHD | Data Scientist

(607) 592-6619 | markcharris81@gmail.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | Atlanta, GA

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a data scientist with a PhD in applied physics who has also taught high school math. I have extensive experience applying math to the world, including developing and publishing a complex experimental method, applying programming tools to automate work and analyze data, and isolating core concepts to communicate mathematical information to both experts and lay people. I see the big picture and anticipate key details.

### **SKILLS**

Programming: Python, SQL, PySpark, Git, GitHub

Data Tools: Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Matplotlib, Seaborn, BeautifulSoup, Streamlit Machine Learning Methods: Regression, Classification, Clustering, Time Series Analysis, Neural Networks Data Science Applications: Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Data Visualization

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Data Science Instructor Associate - Contractor, General Assembly, Remote

6/2022 - present

- Assisted instruction of courses covering Python and Data Analysis using Pandas, SQL, and Tableau.
- Communicated with students about their needs and helped them solve problems and understand core concepts.

# Physics Teacher, Dunwoody High School, Dunwoody, GA

11/2022 - present

- Filled mid-school year need for a physics teacher, including in-progress AP physics classes.
- Took on responsibility for existing classes, quickly adapting to finish them as strongly as possible.
- Supported students preparing for the AP physics exam after a disrupted school year.

## Data Science Immersive Fellow, General Assembly, Remote

9/2021 - 12/2021

- Learned and applied data science and machine learning skills in a 480-hour immersive program, completing 6 projects, 21 lab assignments, and 6 quizzes.
- Completed data science projects include, but are not limited to:
  - Snow Vision Capstone Project: Trained a convolutional neural net to classify images with falling snow.
  - Food Deserts Group Project: Collaborated with two other data scientists using Git to analyze food deserts and health with interpretable regression and classification models and geographical data.
  - Reddit NLP Project: Classified posts acquired via API as being from either the science or futurology subreddits using NLP and multiple classification models, achieving 83.5% accuracy.

## Mathematics Teacher, Dunwoody High School, Dunwoody, GA

7/2016 - 5/2021

- Taught high school math classes from Algebra to Multivariable Calculus and sponsored the Math Team.
- Planned syllabus and lessons as sole teacher for AP Calculus BC and Multivariable Calculus courses, identifying key concepts, breaking them into their essential parts, and highlighting connected ideas.
- Collaborated with colleagues to develop lessons and common assessments to identify student needs.
- Organized and supervised student groups of up to 12 on trips to weekend math competitions.

### Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

8/2004 - 8/2014

- <u>Published a novel biophysical experiment</u> that combined atomic force microscopy, TIRF microscopy, and custom data analysis to measure binding interactions between secretory vesicles and cell membranes.
- Programmed Python script to automate portions of experiment for accuracy and reproducibility.
- Categorized events in over 5 GB data and analyzed their properties with the aid of IGOR Pro scripts.
- Applied statistical analysis to identify a characteristic behavior dependent on experimental conditions.
- Supported courses involving C++ and several other programming, laboratory and physics topics.

### **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Data Science, General Assembly, Remote9/2021 - 12/2021Ph.D. Applied Physics, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY8/2004 - 8/2014B.S. Physics and B.S. Applied Math, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC8/2000 - 5/2004